

#### WER DEVELOPER · PART TIME ANDROID DEVELOPER

101, Pristine Pride Apt. 18th Main, Padmanabhanagar, Chikkalsandra, 560061, Bangalore, India

🛘 (+1) 71-3826-6438 / (+91)991-646-3143 | 🗖 nithin2889@gmail.com | 🌴 nithin2889.github.io/portfolio/ | 🗖 nithin2889 | 🛅 nithpras

"Creating seamless user experiences."

## **Summary**

Currently having 5+ years of experience specializing in web development using Java frameworks like Spring, Hibernate, and HTML and CSS. To optimize, and a scalable code, I use clean architecture for coding. I also have experience working on the RESTful web services to provide SEO friendly URLs. Also, I code in Android in my leisure time. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

## Work Experience

#### **VSM Software / Oracle Financial Services Software**

Bangalore, India

**APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER** 

June. 2014 - Feb. 2017

- · Implemented a front end screen for Flexcube. Wrote PLSQL packages for handling business logic and backend validations.
- Maintained high level of unit test coverage through test-driven development. Implemented Test cases using JUnit and tested web services with RFST Client.
- Experience in Software Development Life Cycle Requirements Analysis, Design, Development, Testing, Deployment and Support.
- Efficient use of various design patterns such as MVC Model-View-Controller, Singleton, DAO Data Access Object, DTO Data Transfer Object.
- Working knowledge of source control (SVN), Maven build tool.
- · Awarded a permanent position in Oracle internally from being a contractor for good performance technically.
- Technologies Used: Java, JSP, Servlets, JSTL, JDBC, JavaScript, Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, RESTful Web Services, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Maven Build Tool, Client-Server and MVC architectures.

#### **Processware Systems Pvt Ltd.**

Bangalore, India

JR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2012 - May. 2014

- Implemented overall Android application logic and implemented RESTful API server to communicate with the BankSoft application backend, along with lead engineer.
- Used Spring Framework along with JSP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript to construct the dynamic web pages presentation layer for the application and to interact with the database for BankSoft front end application.
- Coordinated with clients' team every week to report our progress and update goals.
- Involved in the creation of Class Diagrams, analysis and design of the application.
- Extensively used JavaScript for client side validations.
- **Technologies Used:** Java, Android Framework, RESTful Web Services, JSP, Servlets, JSTL, JDBC, JavaScript/jQuery, Oracle SQL, PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Maven Build Tool, Client-Server and MVC architectures.

### **Education**

#### VTU(Visvesvaraya Technological University)

Bangalore, India

**B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING** 

July. 2011 - July. 2011

• Lead developer and Single Point of Contact for my final year project for which I have been awarded the project completion certificate from ISRO Satellite Center.

# Extracurricular Activity \_

#### Android Nanodegree from Udacity, co-created by Google

Texas, USA

Android Developer

Apr. 2017 - Sept. 2017

- Developed five Android applications as part of the curriculum within 7 months of start of the course and saved 50% on the actual fees.
- Curriculum required developing a Capstone Project where I built an Android app of my own design in two stages. In Stage 1, I designed and planned the app, and in Stage 2, actual app was built using my Stage 1 document as a guide.
- In order to pass all criteria "met specifications". Project was evaluated by a Udacity Code Reviewer according to the prescribed rubric.
- Received rave comments from my Udacity Code Reviewer for my Capstone Project "Giant Bomb A Pocket Games Personalizer". The app will be released to the Google Play Store shortly.
- Experience working extensively on Git and Github and generating signed APKs.